ensure consistency in journals with
realtime Journal
check in business Central there are
multiple ways to check the consistency
and data Integrity of a journal let's go
to a general journal I bring up the tell
me search without q and I search for
General
journals I select the search
result now here I have a journal which I
think I'm done with and I want it to be
checked for consistency
I can of course use the normal preview
posting or the test report actions to
see if the data consistency of my
journal is okay but if I want guidance
in real time there's another option I
can use that's a journal check let's go
enable the journal check let's bring up
the tell me search you type General at
your
setup and select search
result let's find the field enable data
check
and let's enable
it now we go back to the journal
page a new fact box is now visible on
the right side of the page called
Journal check here it shows that there's
an issue with one of the lines and I can
go and click
it there's an amount that should have
been filled on one of the
lines not only does it show the issues
in total it also shows Once you have
focused on a specific line if there is
any issue with that line as in this case
where it shows that the amount is
missing for this specific general
journal line it's a great way to use the
journal check to keep consistency as you
type in business Central thank you for
watching
[Music]